Wake up to reality!
हकीकत को जागो!
Nothing ever goes as planned in this accursed world.
इस शापित दुनिया में कुछ भी योजना के अनुसार नहीं होता।
The longer you live, the more you realize
जितना लंबा तुम जीते हो, उतना ही तुम महसूस करते हो
that the only things that truly exist in this reality...
कि इस हकीकत में वास्तव में जो चीजें मौजूद हैं...
are merely pain, suffering and futility.
वे केवल दर्द, पीड़ा और व्यर्थता हैं।
Listen,
सुनो,
everywhere you look in this world,
इस दुनिया में तुम जहाँ भी देखते हो,
wherever there is light,
जहाँ कहीं भी रोशनी है,
there will always be shadows to be found as well.
वहाँ हमेशा छाया भी मिलेंगी।
As long as there is a concept of victors,
जब तक विजेताओं की अवधारणा है,
the vanquished will also exist.
पराजित भी मौजूद रहेंगे।
The selfish intent of wanting to preserve peace,
शांति बनाए रखने की स्वार्थी इच्छा,
initiates wars...
युद्धों को प्रारंभ करती है...
and hatred is born in order to protect love.
और प्रेम की रक्षा करने के लिए घृणा का जन्म होता है।
There are nexuses...
कुछ ऐसे संबंध होते हैं...
causal relationships that cannot be separated.
कारण संबंध जिन्हें अलग नहीं किया जा सकता।
I want to sever the fate of this world.
मैं इस दुनिया के भाग्य को बदलना चाहता हूँ।
A world of only victors.
केवल विजेताओं की एक दुनिया।
A world of only peace.
केवल शांति की एक दुनिया।
A world of only love.
केवल प्रेम की एक दुनिया।
I will create such a world.
मैं ऐसी दुनिया बनाऊंगा।
I am...
मैं हूँ...
the ghost of the Uchiha.
उचिहा का भूत।
...
...
For truly this reality is a hell.
वास्तव में यह हकीकत एक नर्क है।
— Madara Uchiha A Legendary Villain from "Naruto" CC/Subtitle by Ahsan Habib Muaz
— मदारा उचिहा "नारुतो" से एक दिग्गज खलनायक अनुवाद और उपशीर्षक: अहसान हाबिब मुआज़